so on today's video we are going to do
something super fun and that is we're
going to make a baked Alaska using the
ninja
[Music]
creami so if you don't know what baked
alasker is it's ice
cream on top of a cake base covered in
merang and then whole things put in the
oven and the mering is cooked that way
but without the ice cream melting inside
it's quite a cool kind of dessert I mean
it's straight at the' 70s you got to
love it for that and and it's quite a
unique dessert as well so I thought I'd
give this one A bash here on YouTube so
what are we going to need so for the ice
cream base we are going to start with
380 G of milk and in here we have 3 G of
nutmeg 3 G of cinnamon and 1 G of guarum
in here we have 55 G of skim milk powder
and here we have 40 G of dark brown
sugar and 90 grams of white sugar and
that's just for the ice cream base the
rest we will do after they frozen so
we're going to do this again nice and
easy cuz it's ninja creamy we're going
to take our spices and our gu gum the
spices are because it's Christmas time
so we're going to make this kind of
eggnog flavored vanilla ice cream so
let's just mix up our stabilizer and our
spices pop it in there with the sugar
give that a little stir that but all of
that into our milk along with our milk
powder and stir all that together so
we're now going to pop that in the
microwave and warm this up we're going
to do it in two stages we're can do it
for 1 minute and then probably 30
seconds after
that 1 minute in and that is just to
start adding enough heat to dissolve the
sugars just get that make stirred
together make sure that's completely
combined how is the temperature it's
fine there's no sugar crystals left in
the bottom of that liquid that's all
olved so we actually don't need to go in
for another 30 seconds but what we do
need to do is add our final ingredient
which is or one of our last two final
ingredients and that is 430 G of
whipping cream 33% we are going to put
in two teaspoons of our homemade vanilla
bean paste if you haven't seen the video
I'll put a link in the description below
this is really easy to make and tastes
incred
stir that together one more time this is
the world's worst pouring jug so I'm
going to do it over the
sink and there is our ice
cream so we're going to put that in the
freezer overnight let that harden off
and we will come back to do the whole
assembly to bake Alaska is quite a
timely thing to make because you're
supposed to make the ice cream you're
supposed to mold it into a bowl you know
all the shape and then put it back in
the freezer overnight to harden off I
want to try it with without doing that
so what we're going to do is we're going
to get the oven on 450 F nice and hot
shelf down as low as it will go what
we're going to do is we're going to
prepare our mer first
so we've got what we need here let's
get three egg whites into this bowl egg
whites in balloon Whisk on let's get
these spinning and watchh the egg whites
are whipping we're going to take cream
of TARTA I'm we're going to use qu of a
teaspoon of that and put that in 100 G
of white sugar stir it together and
we're going to start adding into our egg
whites bit by bit just to allow it to
completely dissolve and we're going to
take a Piping Bag with a round nozzle
get it in a cup or glass or a stand add
in one teaspoon of vanilla extract to
your merang until it looks like this
it's glorious Now's the Time to get our
ninja creamy ice cream out of the
freezer we're going to spin it on the
ice cream setting in case you want to
ask it's the same as the gelato setting
whilst that's spinning cuz you know it
takes a while we're going to take a
baking pan get some parchment paper on
there and take some store-bought cake
this is marble cake that I got from
Safeway this morning I have no idea what
it tastes like but we're going to take
two pieces of that and place it onto the
baking pan we're going to join them with
a little piece of our merang and spread
the merang over the top of the cake
finally we're going to load up our
Piping Bag right so there's less sugar
in this ice cream because I don't want
it to go super super soft some of this
onto here we're doing a double bowl
there we go thank
you there we go our oven is up to
temperature I'm actually quite pleased
with the ninja creamy ice cream so
let's get some of this
on going to make sure that all the
little gaps are
covered we don't want that heat getting
in there anywhere make sure there's no
holes all right so with our Roven up to
temperature let's get this in for about
minutes and then we'll see how it looks
keep your fingers crossed we got 30
seconds it's Browning nicely we're going
to get everything ready to get this out
on the top get it on here and see how it
turned
[Music]
out lift this out like that get this pan
out of the
way oh we made it
we made it we got it out of let's get
rid of that we got it out of the oven
baked Alaska straight out of a ninja
creamy do this with any flavor ice cream
you like add flavorings to the mer if
you want to as well I just use vanilla
extract as you
saw I want to kind of cut this
open nice the ice cream is still got
wonderful body to it not it's not melted
it's yeah ninja creamy Baked Alaska with
an eggnog flavored ice cream inside
vanilla flavored mering on top Super
glad this one works out hope you give
this one a try thanks very much for
watching don't forget to like And
subscribe if you want to see more Ninja
creamy recipes and how to do weird
things with Ninja creamies and I will
see you next time
[Music]